the final aspect of how the caches work
concerns the right policy there are
really two parts of it first is the so
called allocate policy which is about do
we insert into the cash meaning allocate
and entering the cash for blogs that we
write so we have a write miss the
question is does the block get brought
to the cash or not there are two types
of caches the first type of cash is
according to this is a write allocate
cash it brings the block that we write
into the cash
the second type does not so when we have
a read miss the block is brought into
the cash but if we have a write miss the
block is not brought into the cash most
cash is today our write allocate simply
because there is some locality between
reads and writes meaning if we write to
something we are also likely to read it
so write allocate helps us have read
hits even if we had a write miss the
other aspect of the right policy is when
we have a write do we write just to the
cash or also to the memory we can have a
write through cache which updates the
memory immediately so pretty much when a
write happens we write to the cache and
we just propagate the write also to
memory that's why it's called right
through because the right kind of goes
through the cache or we can have a write
back cache where we only write to the
cache and we write to the memory only
when the block is replaced from the
cache we cannot just discard the block
at this time because the memory does not
have the most recent version of the
block so the memory has to be updated
once the block is no longer in the cache
but as long as it's in the cache we will
just keep writing to the cache and not
keep memory up-to-date right through is
a very unpopular cache for caches that
send stuff to memory directly we usually
want to have a write back cache because
that way writes which have a lot of
locality will update the cache possibly
many times and only send the write to
memory once once the block is replaced
so we can have many rights and only one
memory right for that
that prevents the memory from being
overwhelmed with the number of rights
that we might have there is also some
relationship between this choice and
this if you have a write-back cache you
want to also have a right allocate cache
because you're saving rights to memory
by writing only to the cache if you have
a right miss you want to have future
rights go to the cache to do right
allocate